Guide to the Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Administration, 1975-2006; Series I
  - Executive Director
    - Cathcart, Kevin
      - Speaking engagements and requests, 1983-1991 (Box 24, Folder 8-14)
      - Speaking (media appearances), 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Special planning meeting, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Staff
        - Memoranda to, 1988-1993 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - Positions
          Includes job descriptions and correspendence.
          - AIDS Law Project
            - Director, 1986 August (Box 25, Folder 4)
            - Paralegal, 1990 March (Box 25, Folder 5)
            - Secretary/staff support, 1990 September (Box 25, Folder 6)
          - Development
            - Assistant, 1989 Apr, October (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
            - Coordinator, 1991 March (Box 25, Folder 9)
          - Education pisition ads, 1991 February (Box 25, Folder 10)
          - Office assistant, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 11)
          - Staff attorney, 1989 November (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Stonewall 25 Planning Group, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Stowell, Sterling, 1987-1991 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Studds, Gerry, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Supreme Court decision, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Supreme Court information and articles, 1985-1988 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Texas Human Rights Foundation, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - TWA Frequent Flyer dispute, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Victim Recovery Program, Fenway Community Health Center, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Victim Witness Assistance Board, 1986-1988 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Wall Street Journal, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - West Publishing, 1988-1990 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - White, Wilda, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Women's law organizations, 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - Women's Legal Defense Fund, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - McWilliams, Denise, audit, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Ross, Josephine
      - Attorney General Task Force, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Bailey, Craig, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - MBA Legal Services Award nomination, 1992-1993 (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - McWilliams, Denise, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Platner, Janice
      - 501c lobbying regulations, 1987-1991 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - AIDS Law Project director (ALPD) job description, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Audit, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Blue Cross, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Department of Public Health, 1995 subcontract, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Drug Free work policy, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Employee census, Circa 1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Grants
        - The Boston Foundation, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Department of Health and Hospitals, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 9)
        - Massachusetts Department of Public Health, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Mailings, Under the Boardwalk, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Malpractice, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - National Lesbian and Gay Law Association, Lavender Law, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Notes and memoranda, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Police Practices Coalition, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Press, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Regionalization, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Staff, 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Bonauto, Mary, audit, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Craig, Amelia
      - Audits, 1987-1996 (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - GLAAD (Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation), 1994-1996 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Intake, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Litigation criteria, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Management Consulting Services, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Strategic planning, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
      - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Buseck, Gary
      - Access Now, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Administration and Finance Committee, 1998-2001 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
      - Administration Assistant advertisement, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Barri, Joe, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Boston Foundation, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Bylaws and articles of organization, 1978-2004 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
      - Criminal Offender Record Information (CORI), 2000-2001 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Development, 1998-2000 (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
      - Fundraising
        - Appeals, 2000-2001 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Information, general, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Hate (fringe) mail, 1992-1999 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Internal Revenue Service, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Kevin Larkin Fund, 1992, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Marketing plan, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Netherland, Julie, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Notes, Undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Public Relations, Communications Committee, 1999-2001 (Box 28, Folder 9-11)
      - Regionalization, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Saltonstall, William, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Strategic planning
        - General, 1996-2000 (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
        - Education, 1999-2001 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Summer Party 2000 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Third Attorney Campaign, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Threshold Foundation, 1996, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - William Haefeli, New Yorker cartoon, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Winter Party, corporate/firm sponsors, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
  - Finance
    - Auditor's reports, 1987-1995 (Box 30, Folder 1-10)
    - Budget/Financial reports, 1979-1996 (Box 30, Folder 11-19)
    - Public charity annual reports, 1980-1995, 2001-2002 (Box 30, Folder 20-29)
  - Office Administration
    - General, 1991-1996 (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1991-1992 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Harvard Divinity School recruiting, 1995-1998 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Law students receptions, 1987-1990 (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
      - Maine marriage event, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Mandy Carter event, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - "Creating Change" notes, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Digital Queers, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Events, 1987-1988 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Freedom to Marry, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Letterhead, Undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Office space search, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Pension, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Personal finance, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of GLAD attorneys, Circa 1980-1999 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Résumés and biographical sketches of GLAD attorneys, 1995-1996 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Retirement, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Sexual harassment policy, 1996-1997 (Box 31, Folder 21)
- Legal, 1990-2008; Series II
  The series consists of reports and litigation and amicus files, including research materials, notes, correspondence, drafts, and briefs. The series contains files for several amicus cases but only one case litigated by GLAD: Bedford and Breen v. New Hampshire Community Technical College. The case challenged the denial of insurance and leave benefits to the families of two New Hampshire state employees based on sexual orientation.
  The series is arranged in three sections: General, Litigation files, and Amicus files. The Litigation files and Amicus files are arranged and labeled as received by the creator.
  - General
    - AIDS Law updates, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Civil Rights updates, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Litigation files, Bedford and Breen v. New Hampshire Community Technical College
    - Pleadings
      - Volume 1, 2002-2005 (Box 32, Folder 3-5)
      - Volume 2, 2005-2008 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
    - Press, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Standard of Review on Appeal, 2004-2005 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Argument outline and notes, Undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - University of New Hampshire domestic partner benefits, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA) law review article, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Deference to pro se litigants, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Snetsinger v. Montana University, 2004-2005 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Koebke briefs and decision, 2004 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Bedford interlocutory transfer, 2004-2005 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Superior court order, 2006 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Cases/treatise regarding "or", 2006 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Bedford / Breen v. NHCTC, 2002-2006 (Box 34, Folder 5-8)
    - Business necessity, 2006 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Bedford waiver of arguments, 2006 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Benefits cases, 2006 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Bedford amicus strategy, 2005-2006 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Bedford expenses submitted to Attorney General, 2008 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - New Hampshire domestic partner imputed taxation, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Brief of Patricia Bedford and Anna Breen, 2006 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Bedford v. New Hampshire Community Technical College, 2002-2003 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Bedford correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Directions, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Breen v. New Hampshire Division of Personnel, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Bedford release for New Hampshire Commission for Human Rights, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Client agreements, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Retainer, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Bedford notes and drafts, 2003-2007 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Bedford contact with SEA, 2006 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Breen damages documentation (affadavit), 2007 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Expenses, Undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Memoranda in Support of the Motions to Reopen Case and Reconsider the Complaints of Patricia Bedford and Anne Breen, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Interlocutory Transfer Statement, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - State Appendix to Interlocutory Transfer, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Superior Court dispositive pleadings, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Settlement on attorney's fees, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Meyer invoice, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Attorney's fees, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - New Hampshire constitutional provisions, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - New Hampshire constitution, how to amend, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - New Hampshire Supreme Court research, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Statutory/Regulation research
      - Statutes, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Anti-discrimination laws, 2003-2004 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Insurance and discrimination, 2003 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - New Hampshire Department of Personnel Regulations, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - New Hampshire state employment statutes, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Adverse impact in 354-A, 2003 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Disparate treatment in 354-A, 2003 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Title VII, 2004-2006 (Box 36, Folder 8-9)
    - Case research
      - Discrimination, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Disparate impact, 2004-2006 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Cases regarding continuing violation, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Rules of Statutory Construction, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Cases cited by Attorney General, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Cases, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 15-18)
      - Collective bargaining agreements and other statutes, 2003 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Cases regarding "similarly situated", 2004 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Supplemental materials, post summary judgement briefing, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Systemic relief, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Amicus files
    - Attorney General v. Desilets
      - Brief Amicus Curiae of the Christian Legal Society, Massachusetts Catholic Conference, National Association of Evangelicals, Catholic League for Religious and Civil Rights, Christian Life Commission of the Southern Baptist Convention, General Conference of Seventh-Day Adventists, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Amicus Curiae of the Institute in Basic Life Principles, Focus on the Family, Concerned Women for America, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Reply Brief of the Plaintiff-Appellant, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Briefs, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Attorney General v. Desilets, Appeal, Joint Appendix, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Evelyn Smith v. Fair Employment and Housing (California), 1994 (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
      - Brief for the Defendants-Appellees, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Brief for the Plaintiff-Appellant, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Motion of Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders and Women's Bar Association for Leave to File Brief Amici Curiae; Brief Amici Curiae of the Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Brief of Amicus Curiae Massachusetts Commission Against Discrimination in Support of Plaintiff-Appellant, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Brief of Amicus Curiae, Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Decision [?], 1994 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Pleadings, 1990-1992 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Ayer-- Richard Sommi v. Samuel Ayer; Samuel Keller v. Samuel Ayer
      - Correspondence and background, 1999-2001 (Box 38, Folder 5-6)
      - Amici, 1999-2001 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Briefs, 1999-2001 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Baehr v. Miike; Baehr v. Lewin
      - Circuit Court, 1995-1996 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Hawaii Supreme Court, 1993-1999 (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
      - Deposition transcripts, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
      - Decisions, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Trial coverage, 1996-2000 (Box 40, Folder 4-5)
      - Brause and Duggan v. Alaska (marriage case), 1997-1999 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Dean v. D.C. (Vermont marriage), 1992-2000 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
      - Marriage, Baehr press releases, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Backlash, Hawaii, Constitutional Convention, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Briefs, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Summary of Trial Proceedings, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - GLAD Amicus Brief, 1996-1997 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Protect Our Constitution (POC) fundraising letter, 1998 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Post-election 1998, 1998-1999 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Postmortem regarding November 1998 election, 1998-1999 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Postmortem analysis, 1998-2000 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Commission on Sexual Orientation and the Law report, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Marriage, Hawaii, Constitutional Amendment, 1996-1999 (Box 42, Folder 8-9)
      - Pleadings, 1991-1997 (Box 43, Folder 1-3)
      - Reciprocal benefits, Hawaii, 1999-2000 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Blixt v. Blixt
      - Amicus, 2001-2002 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Pleadings, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Burns v. Burns
      - Amici, correspondence and notes, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Amicus briefs, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Decision, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Press, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, court documents, and research, 2001-2002 (Box 45, Folder 1-3)
    - Hernandez v. Robles (City Clerk of the City of New York)
      - Correspondence, notes, research, 2006 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - New York materials, 2006 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Brief of Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders as Amicus Curiae, 2006 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Drafts of Amicus brief, 2006 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence and motion for leave to file amicus curiae, 2006 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Mass Equality, "One Year of Marriage Equality" (book of testimonials), 2005 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Decision, 2006 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Local Union No. 12004, United Steelworkers of America v. The Commonwealth of Massachusetts, Brief of Amicus Curiae Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders and Massachusetts Lesbian & Gay Bar Association (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Melynchenko v. 84 Lumber Company
      - Briefs, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
      - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Transcript, Volumes 4 and 5, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
      - Appendix to Brief, Circa 1994 (Box 47, Folder 3-4)
    - Muzzy v. Cahillane Motors
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Brief for Plaintiff-Appellant, Susan Muzzy, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Brief of Cahillane Motors, Inc., 2000 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Research, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
      - Brief for Plaintiff-Appellant, Susan Muzzy, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Brief of Amici Curiae Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders and Women's Bar Association of Massachusetts, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Protective Life Insurance v. Sullivan
      - Correspondence and notes, 1998-1999 (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
      - Cases/Articles, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Incontestability cases, Circa 1996 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Statistics, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Statutory construction, Circa 1996 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Authority of Insurance Commissioner cases, Circa 1996 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Appeal, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Amicus Curiae (draft?), 1996 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Brief of Appellants Dignity Viatical Settlement Partners, L.P., and Dignity Partners, Inc., 1996 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Briefs, affidavit, decision, notes, 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Reply Brief of Appellants Dignity Viatical Settlement Partners, L.P., and Dignity Partners, Inc. (Court of Appeals), 1996[?] (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Reply Brief of Appellants Dignity Viatical Settlement Partners, L.P., and Dignity Partners, Inc. (Supreme Judicial Court of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts), 1997 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Brief of Amicus Curiae American Council of Life Insurance, 1996 April 4 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Brief of Amicus Curiae American Council of Life Insurance, 1996 November 27 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Certified questions and opinion, Circa 1996 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Brief of Amici Curiae AIDS Law Project Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders, AIDS Action Committee of Massachusetts, Inc., Catholic Charitable Bureau of the Archdiocese of Boston, Inc., Massachusetts, Breast Cancer Coalition, and Boston Pediatric and Family AIDS Project, 1996 October 8 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Viatical briefs, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Pleadings, 1996-1997 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Notes and Brief of Appellants Dignity Viatical Settlement Partners, L.P., and Dignity Partners, Inc., 1995-1996 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Notes/Drafts, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Brief of Plaintiff-Appellee (2 copies), 1996 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, briefs, and drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - News clippings and briefs, 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Briefs with notes, 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Notes and research, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Public Affairs & Education, 1976-2010; Series III
  The series documents the public affairs and education activities of GLAD, both before and after the establishment of a formal Public Affairs & Education department circa 1990. Of particular interest are GLAD's annual reports and a near-complete run of GLAD Briefs, GLAD's public outreach newsletter, which has been published continually since 1979. The series also contains records documenting strategic planning and public affairs administration; a large number of GLAD publications, used primarily for public education; news clippings primarily related to GLAD's cases and issues of interest to GLAD; materials relating to the InfoLine and Lawyer Referral Service. The series also contains a substantial number of files documenting anti-gay and lesbian voter inititatives in Maine and efforts to block them.
  The series is arranged in six sections: Public Affairs, Education, Maine, Speaking engagements, Volunteers, and Coalitions.
  - Public Affairs
    - General
      - Advertising, 1998-1999 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Bonauto, Mary
        - Correspondence with Nick Kouros, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Goodridge press, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - "Letters to the Editor" project, 1998-2001 (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Marriage, 2002-2003 (Box 52, Folder 5)
        - Public relations articles, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 6)
        - Speaking engagements, 2002-2003 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Communications / Public relations strategy, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Contacts (press), Undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1985-2001 (Box 53, Folder 2-3)
      - Focus group memoranda, 2001 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Lambda Legal press memoranda, 1993-1995 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Meeting notes, 1997-1998 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Outreach, general, 2001 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Photographs, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Radio, Circa 2002 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Send logs, 1995-2002 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Social events, Undated (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Strategic planning, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Television, Circa 2002 (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - Twentieth anniversary photograph list, Circa 1998 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Press
      - Articles by GLAD attorneys, 1988-2005 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Media strategy, 2001-2002 (Box 83, Folder 1)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Restricted until January 1, 2036.
      - Planning
        - Abbott v. Bragdon, 1998 (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - Baker v. State, 2000 (Box 54, Folder 2)
        - Vermont and Massachusetts marriage cases, 1999-2000 (Box 54, Folder 3)
        - Vermont marriage
          - Decision, press contacts, 1999 (Box 54, Folder 4)
          - Strategy, 1997 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Press releases, 1980-2003 (Box 54, Folder 6-10)
      - Talking points
        - Hawaii marriage decision, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 11)
        - Vermont marriage, 2000 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - News clippings/coverage
        - General
          - 1980-2000 (Box 55, Folder 1-8)
          - 2000-2005 (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
          - Undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
          - Gay press, 1991-1992 (Box 56, Folder 5-6)
        - Subjects
          - Abbott v. Bragdon, 1996-1998 (Box 56, Folder 7-8)
          - AIDS, 1985-1987, 1996, undated (Box 57, Folder 1-4)
          - AIDS quilt, 1987 (Box 57, Folder 5)
          - Anti-gay violence, 1988-1990 (Box 57, Folder 6)
          - Bonauto, Mary, 1990-2000 (Box 57, Folder 7)
          - Buckley case, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 8)
          - Ceria case, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 9)
          - Civil rights, Circa 1986-1991 (Box 57, Folder 10)
          - Civil union, Vermont
            - News clippings, 1990-2000 (Box 57, Folder 11-13)
            - Talk of the Nation with Lippert, Bill Eskridge, and Gary Bauer [commercially produced], 2000 March 22; 1 (Box 92)
              Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository.
          - Detroit bookstore advertisement controversy, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 1)
          - Domestic partners, Circa 1989-1990 (Box 58, Folder 2)
          - Duffy, Michael, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 3)
          - Equal Rights Amendment, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 4)
          - Foster care, 1985-1990 (Box 58, Folder 5-8)
          - GLAD history, 1982-1990 (Box 58, Folder 9)
          - Gay Community News, articles regarding GLAD, 1983-1984, undated (Box 58, Folder 10-11)
          - Gay rights bill, 1986-1990 (Box 59, Folder 1)
          - Gay workers, 1980-1991 (Box 59, Folder 2)
          - Hardwick, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 3)
          - Kennedy School of Government, 1990-1991 (Box 59, Folder 4)
          - Krolikowski case, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 5)
          - Marriage
            - Backlash, 2003 (Box 59, Folder 6)